Mahdieh Zabihimayvan

Curriculum Vitae

Phone: (937) 775-5217 Email: Zabihimayvan.2@wright.edu,

Home page: http://knoesis.org/mahdieh mahdieh@knoesis.org Current Location: Dayton, Ohio, USA

Personal Statement

I am a PhD candidate of computer science and a graduate research assistant working on machine learning and anomaly detection. Through several theoretical and applied projects, I have explored various concepts from computer networks and web mining to machine learning and soft computing techniques. I am fascinated with using machine learning and statistical analysis in anomaly detection for different fields from cyber security to defect detection in physical objects.

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science (GPA:4.0)

2017-Present Wright State University, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

Focus: Machine learning, soft computing, Web mining, anomaly detection, statistical

M.S., Computer Engineering-Software (GPA:4.0)

2012-2014

Imam Reza International University, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

Thesis: A Proposed Algorithm Based on Markov Clustering for Web Robot Detection Focus: Evolutionary computation and optimization methods, machine learning, soft

computing, data mining

B.S., Computer Engineering-Software

Ferdowsi University, Dept. of Computer Engineering, Iran

Advisor: Dr. Mohsen Kahani

Thesis: Designing and Implementing a Web-based Account Framework Focus: Computer networks, web programming, database design development

Research Experience

Wright State University, Dayton, Ohio, USA

Graduate Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Dr. Derek Doran

• Machine learning and soft computing techniques in anomaly detection and web mining (MATLAB, Python, R, Java, JavaScript)

• Statistical Analysis and machine learning models in data characterization (R, Python)

2017-Present

2007-2011

Imam Reza International University, Mashhad, Iran

2014-2016

Department of Computer and Information Technology

Advisor: Dr. Majid Vafaei Jahan

- Dynamic feature selection based on Fuzzy Rough Set theory (MATLAB)
- Soft computing techniques in web session detection (MATLAB)
- Markov processes with focus on Markov Clustering algorithm (MATLAB)
- Using Fuzzy Inference System based on decision trees as web visitor classification (MATLAB)
- Evolutionary computing techniques as web traffic classifiers (MATLAB)
- Data mining techniques in processing data (Weka, MATLAB)

Ferdowsi University, Iran

2011-2012

Information and Communication Center, Network & Web developing Group

- Web programming (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, HTML)
- Network management and Security

Mashhad University of Medical Science (MUMS), Iran

2009

Information Technology Center, Web Designing Group

- Web programming (CSS, HTML) and designing websites
- Working with content management systems based on Microsoft SharePoint

Teaching Experience

Imam Reza International University, Iran

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer and Information Technology

2012-2014

- Teaching Assistant of data mining for M.S. Students
 - o Teaching data mining tools in MATLAB and Weka
- Teaching Assistant of advanced engineering mathematics in software engineering for M.S. Students
 - o Statistical analysis and tests, random number generations, finite Markov chain and its algorithmic application
- Teaching Assistant of computer performance evaluation and modeling for M.S. Students
 - o Queueing networks and Markov chains, Markov processes for stochastic modeling, test functions for optimization needs, Fuzzy control of queueing system, hidden Markov model
- Algorithm design for B.S. students
 - o Time complexity of algorithms, recursion equations, sort algorithms, dynamic programming

Technical Qualifications

Database Programming: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Microsoft Access

Programming Language: Python, R, MATLAB, Java, JavaScript, PHP, CSS, HTML

Data Mining Tools: MATLAB, Python, R

Selected Publications

- M. Zabihimayvan, Reza Sadeghi, D. Doran, Mehdi Allahyari (2019), "A Broad Evaluation of the Tor English Content Ecosystem", The Web Conference (Submitted).
- M. Zabihimayvan, D. Doran (2018), "Some (Non-)Universal Features of Web Robot Traffic," 52th Annual Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), IEEE, Princeton University, NJ, US, (Accepted).
- M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi, N. Rude, D. Doran (2017), "A Soft Computing Approach for Benign and Malicious Web Robot Detection," Expert Systems with applications, 87, 129-140, (Impact factor: 3.928).
- J. Hamidzadeh, M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi (2017), "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy rough sets," Soft Computing, In Press, (Impact factor: 2.472).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A Density Based Clustering Approach for Web Robot Detection," The 4th International IEEE conference on Computer and knowledge Engineering, IEEE, (Accept Rate: 22%).
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "A density based clustering approach to distinguish between web robot and human requests to a web server," The ISC International Journal of Information Security, 6(1), 77-89.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan, J. Hamidzadeh (2014), "Fuzzy Inference for Intrusion Detection of Web Robots in Computer Networks," 45th Annual Iranian Mathematics Conference, In Persian.
- M. Zabihimayyan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2014), "An Optimum Markov Clustering Algorithm for Accurate Web Robots Detection," The 7th International Conference of Iranian Operations Research Society, In Persian.
- M. Zabihimayvan, M. Vafaei Jahan (2013), "Web Robot Detection with Fuzzy Inference System Based on Decision Trees," The Seventh International Iranian Data Mining Conference, In Persian.

Patent

M. Zabihimayvan, R. Sadeghi, D. Doran (2018), "Soft Computing Methods for Feature Selection for Web Agent Detection", June 2018, U.S. Provisional Patent, Pending.

Honors and Awards

• Anita Borg Scholar at Grace Hopper, Houston, Texas	2018
Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Wright State University	
• CRA-W Grad Cohort Scholar, San Francisco, California	2018
Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Wright State University	
• Top researcher of M.Sc. students of Software Engineering	2017
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Best paper award for publishing the paper titled "Detection of Web site visitors based on fuzzy	2016
rough sets"	
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Ranked 2nd in the academic period among the students matriculated from 2012 to 2014	2014
Dept. of Computer and Information Technology, International University of Imam Reza	
• Ranked 2nd among participants in Nationwide Azad Universities Entrance Exam for graduate	2011
studies	

• Ranked Top 1% among over 300,000 participants in *nationwide* universities entrance exam for undergraduate studies

Research service

Journal referee at Computers and Security Program Committee member of the Web Conference 2018 Journal referee at IEEE Transactions on Fuzzy Systems Journal referee at Medical Internet Research